HDZIMU中文字幕網 http://www.hdzimu.com
遠鑒字幕組製作
[Visionary] 0day-sub
翻譯&校對：william2568 rix
他們遲到了
They're late.
布倫達 我們馬上就到
Brenda, we're coming up behind.
拖住他們
Keep 'em busy.
坐穩
Hang on!
快報告
Call it in!
這堿O019號列車
Transport zero-one-niner,
我們行進中遭遇襲擊
we got trouble on the rail line.
23英里處 快來支援
Mile 23, send backup! Send backup!
收到 馬上趕來
Roger that. On our way.
太瘋狂了 托馬斯
This is crazy, Thomas!
坐穩了
Hang on.
再靠近一點
Get me closer!
上來 文斯
Come on, Vince!
文斯
Vince!
快跳
Jump!
該死
Shit!
我們走
Let's go!
嘿 飛行器來了
Hey! Berg!
019號列車 請注意
Zero-one-niner, be advised.
有可疑人物登上車尾
You've taken on boarders at the rear.
我們立即發動進攻
We're engaging the truck now.
布倫達 有敵人來了
Hey, Brenda, you got company!
快
Go, go, go!
立即開火
Open fire.
天哪 小心
Watch out!
該死的
Holy shit!
托馬斯 靠你自己了 堅持住
Thomas, you're on your own. Don't die.
祝你好運
Good luck!
我們該行動了 快
We gotta move. Come on!
快 快 聽到了沒有
Go, go! You heard him!
把包給我
Give me the bag!
射擊
Shoot!
隱蔽 臥倒
Get down! Get down!
文斯 小心 手榴彈
Vince?
弄好了 快躲起來
We're set! Cover your ass!
前進 快 快
Go, go, go!
躲起來
Take cover!
前進 快走
Come on! Let's go! Let's go!
後五節車廂遭到劫持 趕快停車
We lost the rear five. Stop the train!
紐特
Newt!
好了 來吧 我們走
All right, come on, let's go. Come on!
米諾
Minho!
米諾 能聽見嘛
Minho, can you hear me?
這 這
This one. This one!
糟糕
Oh, shit!
很快就過來了
It's gonna be close.
狡猾的小混蛋
Squirrelly bastard.
我們能搞定的
We got 'em! We got 'em!
馬上下車 舉起雙手
Step out of the vehicle with your hands up.
我們走 各位
Let's go, boys.
停在那 不要動
Stop right there. Don't move.
我說了不要動 混蛋
I said freeze, asshole!
都聽你的 兄弟
Whatever you say, hermano.
快攔住他
Hold him back!
你可不要亂來
Y'all don't wanna do that now.
煎鍋
Hey, Fry.
我們又見面了 快點 退後
Good to see you guys. Go on, back up.
嗨
Hi.
紐特 怎麼樣了
Newt, how you doing?
不要催我
Don't rush me.
紐特 快上來
Newt, get up here.
馬上就去
Almost there.
紐特 快走
Newt, go!
他們哪兒去了 我不知道
- Where the hell are they? - I don't know!
走 他們人太多了
Go! There's too many of them!
好了 夥計們 我們來了
All right, boys, we're here!
繼續前進
Keep moving!
快點 低點
- Come on! - Lower!
掩護我
Cover me!
快
Go, go!
好 準備好了
All right, we're clear!
起飛了
Okay, we're going up.
文斯 趕快上來
Vince, get up here!
上來 文斯
Now, Vince!
我們就要回家了
We're going home, baby!
太好了
Yeah!
很好 夥計們 幹得好
All right, guys! Good job. Whoo!
耶
Yeah!
阿里斯
Aris.
你們沒事吧
Hey, you guys okay?
沒事
Yeah, we're fine.
天哪
Jesus.
沒事就好 別怕
There you are. Oh, God!
你們沒事了 好嗎 先等會兒
It's okay. You guys are safe. All right? Just hang on.
我需要斷線鉗
I need the bolt cutters.
你還好吧
Are you okay?
我沒事 你怎麼樣
I'm fine. How are you?
他不在
He's not here.
我拿一個
I'll take one.
這邊來 你們安全了
Come on down. You're safe here.
需要救治 往左邊走
Need medical attention, move to your left.
我需要急救
I need first aid.
這邊 各位 過來
Right this way, guys. Come on down here.
大家都過來
Come on in, guys!
好了 這邊
Okay, guys, over here!
聽好了
All right, listen up.
我知道你們受盡折磨
I know you've all been through hell.
我也很想說 一切都過去了
I wish I could say our troubles are over.
但一切還沒結束
But we're not through this yet.
實驗部虎視眈眈 不肯放棄
WICKED's still out there. They're not giving up.
因為他們想利用你們
'Cause you got something they want.
他們抓你們是因為
They took you because you're immune
你們對一種能夠滅絕人類的病毒免疫
to a plague that's wiping out the human race.
他們認為應該犧牲你們研製解藥
And they think you're worth sacrificing to find a cure.
可我反對
Well, I don't.
所以兩天後
So in two days,
等我們把這艘船改造好
when we get this tub of rust seaworthy,
我們就離開這
we're getting the hell outta here.
去一個
We're gonna go to a place
實驗部找不到你們的地方
where WICKED will never find you.
在那堶奐s開始
A place you can start over.
在那埵w家
A place you can call home.
你們願意嗎
Are you with me?
快上船 開始幹活吧
Come on up here. Let's get to work.
快點 我需要幫手
Come on, I need some volunteers.
來吧
Let's go.
開始幹活
Let's get to work.
把板條釘到船上
Let's get these crates on the boat.
我們兩天後就出發
We got two days before we leave.
過來幫我個忙
All right. Give me a hand up here.
有什麼事嗎
May I help you?
看起來還行
It looks good.
好極了
How you feeling?
就隨便問問
Awesome.
我知道 你就隨便問問
I was just asking.
大家都是隨便問問
I know, I know, you're just asking.
別擔心
Everybody's just asking.
如果感染了
Don't worry. When I Crank out,
我第一個告訴你 行嗎
you'll be the first to know, okay?
給你 喝點吧
Here, drink this.
你們怎麼這麼久才來
Took you guys long enough to rescue us.
總算見到你了 夥計
It's good to see you, too, bud.
怎麼回事
So what happened?
我反擊了
I fought back.
我們嘗試過了
Tried to, anyway.
能找到我們不容易
You're lucky you found us at all.
他們到處轉移我們
They had us on the move a lot.
好像內部出了什麼事
It felt like something big was happening.
知道他們要去哪兒嗎
Any idea where they were heading?
我只知道
All I know is
他們經常提及一座城市
they kept talking about a city.
我覺得 現在應該已經沒有城市了吧
I didn't think there were any cities left.
是沒什麼城市了
That's because there aren't.
就算有也是廢墟
Not still standing, anyway.
好了 等等 米諾在哪
Okay, wait. What about Minho?
他怎麼不在火車上
Why wasn't he on the train?
抱歉 托馬斯
I'm sorry, Thomas.
他之前在
He was.
他們帶走了四五十個人
They got 40, maybe 50 kids.
具體數字還在統計
We're still compiling an official count,
飛行員看得很清楚
but the pilot got a good look.
應該是他們
He thinks it was them.
當然是他們
Of course it was them.
飛行器呢
What about the Berg?
我們追蹤了幾英里
We tracked it a few miles.
但他們拆了定位器
But someone must have known about the locator.
不見蹤影了
They're totally off the grid.
快走 免疫者
Move it, Immunes.
C22.
B9.
我們還在搜索附近區域
We're searching the area,
但是他們可能早就離開了
but they're probably long gone by now.
不會 他們哪兒都不會去的
Oh, no, they're not going anywhere.
他還沒救走最想救的人
He didn't get what he really wanted.
這 就這
There, that's it.
大概幾百英里遠
It's a few hundred miles.
根據火車線路
Based on the railways,
和阿里斯提供的消息
everything that Aris told us,
他們肯定是要去這
that's gotta be where they're headed.
帶米諾去這
That's where they're taking Minho.
我們帶上所有人
We take everyone who can fight.
沿路追蹤下去
Follow the roads where we can.
一周內就能回來
We can make it back within a week.
一周
A week?
我們花了六個月才走到今天這一步
It took us six months to get here.
現在我們已經有100多人了
We got over 100 kids here now.
我們不能一直留在這
We can't just hang out here forever
畢竟鬧出了大動靜
after what we just pulled.
你在地圖上
You wanna wander off
隨便指個地方就說要去
to some random point on the map.
你都不清楚那堛滷〞p
You don't even know what's there.
我知道
I do.
那是幾年前了
It's been a few years,
但我去過
but I've been there.
最後的城市
The Last City.
實驗部這麼叫它
That's what WICKED called it.
那堿O他們的大本營
It was their whole base of operations.
如果那座城市還在
If that city is still standing,
你最好離它遠點 夥計
that's the last place you wanna go, hermano.
那就是個狼窩
That's the lion's den.
我們什麼沒闖過
It's nothing we haven't done before.
對 但需要周密的計劃
Yeah, with months of planning,
準確可靠的情報 行動要隱秘
and reliable information, the element of surprise,
可現在這些要素都不具備
none of which we have now.
文斯 我想好了
Vince, I've thought this through.
你能聽我說完嗎
Would you just hear me out?
上次我們沒準備好就行動
The last time we went off half-cocked...
我失去了一切
I lost everything.
你還記得嗎
You remember that?
我知道要救米諾 好嗎
Look, I know it's Minho. All right?
但我不能不顧這些孩子的安危
But you can't ask me to put those kids
去救他一個
on the line for one man.
我做不到
I won't do it.
搜索該區域
Searching the grid now.
A區完畢
A is completed.
開始搜索B區
Scanning B-sector now.
糟了 快關燈
Shit. Hit the lights.
快走 快走
Let's go, let's go!
天哪 他們找過來了
Jeez, they're getting close.
說對了
You're right.
不能留在這
We can't stay here.
你這是要去哪兒
Where do you think you're going then?
紐特
Newt...
你別多說了
Don't be a twat about it.
我也一起
I'm already in.
走吧
Come on.
不 這次不行
No. No, not this time.
聽我說
Look,
就算我們找到米諾
even if we find Minho,
也未必能安全地逃出來
there's no guarantee we make it back from this.
那你就更需要幫手了 不是嗎
Well, you'll need all the help you can get then, won't you?
我們一起死堸k生
Well, we started this together.
現在也要一起去救他
May as well end it that way, too.
好吧
Okay.
一起去救他
Let's go get him back.
不不
No.
等等
Hey!
Hey! No, no, no. Wait. Hey!
沒事的
Hey, wait, wait! Hey, it's okay! Hey!
他情況怎樣
How's he doing?
呼吸狀況還不錯
Breathing levels look strong.
不
Oh, shit!
No! No!
雖然效果不如迷宮
It's not as effective as the maze,
但似乎也有作用
but it seems to be working.
那就好
It's promising.
但我們還需要更多的試驗品
But we'll need a larger sample to work with.
明白了
All right.
繼續
Carry on.
不  不  不
No! No!
你想讓我們通過那
You want us to go in there?
我也不想說這種嚇人的話
I don't wanna come across as too negative,
但這堨i是狂客
but if I was a Crank,
最喜歡出沒的地方
that's exactly where I would be.
但我們現在別無選擇
I don't think we have much of a choice.
那走吧 我坐副駕
All right. I get shotgun.
我們進來了
Well, here we go.
好 小心 開慢點
Yeah, just take it nice and slow.
沒事 只有一個
It's okay. It's just one,
那就慢慢開繞過他
so take it slow, go around him.
不要緊的
We'll be fine.
慢慢開
Take it slow.
求求你
Please.
幫幫我
Help me.
求求你
Please.
求你了 讓我進去
Please! Let me in.
好了 煎鍋 不要停
- Okay. Fry, we gotta go. - Please! Open the door.
求你了 繼續開
- You need to go right now! - Why won't you open it?
快踩油門 煎鍋
Just floor it, Fry!
快 快點 加速
- Hold on! - Floor it! Come on!
快點 煎鍋 甩掉他 我在甩
- Come on, Fry, shake him! - I'm trying!
快
Go.
坐穩了
Hang on!
天哪
Oh, God.
煎鍋 小心
Frypan, watch out!
都沒事吧 我沒事
Everyone okay?
我的手
My hand.
煎鍋 閉上眼睛
Fry, cover your eyes.
見鬼 你沒事吧 沒事 你呢
Oh, shit. You okay, man?
見鬼 我的手
- Yeah. You all right? - Shit, my hand.
等等 托馬斯
Wait! Thomas!
托馬斯 車門
Thomas, the door!
你能出來嗎
Can you get out?
見鬼 好了 能出來嗎
Oh, shit. All right.
紐特 沒事吧   煎鍋 去那邊
- Newt, you all right? - Fry, go around.
我想辦法出去
I'm trying to get out.
紐特 你沒事吧
Newt, you okay?
我沒事
Yeah, I think so.
煎鍋 沒事啊
Fry, you good?
見鬼
Oh, shit.
煎鍋 我們得趕緊走
Frypan, I think we gotta move.
快 等一會
- Now! - Wait a minute!
快點 煎鍋 快 快
- Right now! - Fry, now!
你在幹什麼 趕緊走 快啊 快走
Come on, what are you doing? We gotta move! Come on!
等等 煎鍋 你磨蹭什麼
- Come on! - Hold on!
煎鍋 快走 快啊 等等
- Frypan gotta go! Come on! - Wait!
快點
Come on!
打得好 煎鍋 謝謝
- Nice shot, Fry. - Thanks.
好了 我們快走
Okay. We gotta go.
走 走
Go, go!
煎鍋 快啊 快走
Fry, come on, let's go!
煎鍋 我們走 快走 快 快
- Fry, let's move, let's go! - Go! Go! Go!
小心
Watch out.
煎鍋 能搞定嗎 能
- Fry, you got any left? - Yeah!
好的 這邊 這邊
Okay. This way, this way!
行了 另一邊 另一邊
Okay, Fry. Other way, other way!
沒子彈了
I'm out!
見鬼
Shit!
快進來
Hey, get in!
快 豪爾赫 快 快
- Go, Jorge, go! - Go!
挺住
Hang on!
真不簡單
I'm impressed!
你們撐了差不多一整天
You guys almost lasted a whole day.
沒事吧 沒事
- You good? - Yeah.
抱歉 連累你們也跟著冒險
I'm sorry. I didn't wanna bring you guys into this.
我覺得他想說
I think what he's trying to say
謝謝你救了我們
is thanks for saving us.
不用客氣
You're welcome.
別高興太早
Hey, don't get your hopes up.
那邊的關卡
That checkpoint back there,
是這座城的最後的防線
that was the city's last defense.
如果那媥D到突破 這座城將在劫難逃
If that was overrun, chances are the city is, too.
是的 除非他們能想到
Yeah, unless they figured out
別的辦法把狂客阻擋在外面
some other way to keep the Cranks out.
有意思
Funny...
我們關在堶惜F三年
Spent three years trapped behind walls,
拚命逃了出來
trying to break out,
現在卻又要衝回去
and now we wanna break back in.
是啊 太諷刺了
Yeah. It's hilarious.
豪爾赫 我們該怎麼進去
Jorge, how do we get in?
別問我 兄弟
Don't look at me, hermano.
那些牆是新建的
Those walls are new.
實驗部最會這一招了
I guess that's WICKED's answer for everything.
站在這可沒法弄清楚
Well, we ain't gonna figure it out from up here.
出發吧
Let's go!
你真的覺得他在那
You really think he's in there?
去了就知道了
I guess we'll find out.
你知道特瑞莎應該也在那塈a
You know she's gonna be there, too.
我們想要的一切 必須確保有足夠的資源
We just have to make sure we have the resources.
我再聯繫你 很抱歉
And I'll keep in touch. Excuse me.
準備好了
Are you ready?
沒事的
It'll be fine.
大家已經開始喪失信心 博士
People are beginning to lose faith, Doctor.
當初你封閉圍牆時 你向我們保證
When you sealed off the walls, you assured us
那只是臨時預防措施
that it would only be a temporary precaution.
為什麼現在還沒有解禁
Why have you now denied all entry?
因為情況有變 情況惡化了
Because things are changing. And not for the better.
感染率上升了百分之三百
Infection rates were up 300%.
幸運的是
Fortunately,
我們技術上可能就要迎來突破了
we may be on the verge of a breakthrough.
這就是A7號實驗體
This is Subject A7.
他之前在迷宮堳搕F三年多
He spent over three years in the Maze Trials.
而且他體內產生的抗體
The antibodies produced in response
是我們見過最強的
have been the strongest we've ever seen.
我們正在提取一種新型血清
We're extracting a new serum as we speak.
如果你們同意的話
And with your support,
我們就可以展開人體實驗
we'd like to begin human trials.
謝謝你 博士 很不錯
Thank you, Doctor. That is very impressive.
但我們已經試過這種方法了
But we have been down this road before.
坦白地說 我們都開始懷疑...
Frankly, we are all beginning to wonder if...
我們的資源是否應該用於別的地方
If our resources couldn't be better spent elsewhere.
- 你是說 - 建立安全區
- Meaning? - Safe zones.
建和這一樣的保護區
Protected areas like the one we're in.
這樣我們能盡可能救更多的人
We could save as many people as possible.
能救多少
How many?
一千個
A thousand?
兩千個
Two thousand?
你能保證這些安全區
And that's assuming your protected areas
就一定安全嗎
stay protected,
你知道這是不可能的
which we know they won't.
被感染的人數已經是健康人數的三倍
The infected already outnumber the healthy three-to-one.
安全區只能延緩死亡的到來
All you'd be doing is delaying the inevitable.
你們有沒有親人因病毒感染而亡
Have any of you ever lost someone to the virus?
我侄女
A niece.
安娜
Anna.
很抱歉沒能幫到她
I'm sorry we weren't able to help her.
但試想 如果我們能戰勝這種病毒
But imagine if we were able to live with the virus.
活了下來
To survive it.
試想 你當時可以告訴安娜
Imagine being able to tell Anna
你能讓她過上正常的生活
that you could give her the chance to live a normal life.
我們現在已經無比接近解藥研製成功了
We've never been this close to a cure.
我們犧牲了很多才走到這一步
And we've sacrificed a lot to get this far.
請不要
Please,
讓這些犧牲付諸東流
don't let those sacrifices be for nothing.
做的不錯
Nicely done.
他們不好說話 你表現得非常好
They can be a tough crowd. You handled them perfectly.
延緩死亡的到來
"Delaying the inevitable."
托馬斯以前經常這樣說我們
Thomas used to say the same about us.
你還經常想他嗎
Do you still think about him?
我可以幫助你刪除記憶
I can help you with that, those memories.
沒必要揪著過去不放
There's no reason to keep holding on to them.
刪掉就行了
It's a simple procedure.
我不想刪掉是有原因的
There is a reason.
我想記住
I want to remember.
找到解藥
If we find a cure,
所有的付出才值得
that's the only way all this was worth it.
但願你是對的
I hope you're right.
這堹}壞的很嚴重
This place has really gone through hell.
我們不要走散了
We just gotta stay together.
我們是那些
We are the voice
無聲者的代言人
of the voiceless!
而他們藏在高牆之內
They hide behind their walls,
還幻想著可以獨佔解藥
thinking they can keep the cure for themselves,
然後看著其他人慢慢地死亡 腐爛
while they watch the rest of us wither and rot!
但我們的人數
But there are more of us
比他們多得多
than there are of them.
我提議 大家站起來
And I say,
拿回屬於我們的東西
we rise up
讓我們一起
and take back what is ours!
奪取勝利吧
Let's bring back a victory!
去通知詹森
Get Janson.
讓我們進去
Let us in!
就是那兒 從那兒進去
That's it. That's our way in.
讓我們進去
Let us in!
To the wall!
讓我們進去 我要進去
Let us in! Let us in! Let us in!
托馬斯
Thomas!
應該不是這個地方
This is not what you're looking for.
這麼多人拚命想進去
All these people trying to find their way in,
你覺得你能有新發現嗎
you think you're gonna find something they can't?
走了這麼遠 我不想現在回頭
Came this far. I'm not turning back now.
我們怎麼捲進了這種事
What the hell did we get ourselves into?
快點走啊 給我讓開
Get out of my way! Get out of my way!
托馬斯 我感覺不太對
Thomas, this doesn't feel right.
你說對了 先生
You were right, sir.
無人機剛剛在牆外發現了他
The drone sweep picked him up outside the walls.
準備開火
Get the guns online.
各位 我們得走了 快看
Hey, guys, we gotta go now. Look.
快走 我們走 快啊 我們走
Let's go, let's go!
托馬斯 我們走
- Thomas, let's go. - We gotta get out of here!
我們離開這 快走
Let's go! Let's go!
快離開這 托馬斯
Go! Go! Go! Come on!
快點
Go! Keep going!
快跑
Come on!
Move!
躲起來 進來
Come on! Get in! Get in!
快點 他們來了 快
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
快點 跑
Come on!
- 沒路走了 - 快
- No way out! - Come on!
快點 紐特
Newt! Newt!
把手給我拿開
Get your hands off of me!
不 布倫達
No! Brenda!
布倫達
Brenda! Brenda!
快 快
Go, go, go!
放開我
Get off me! Get off me!
派人出去找
Send out a patrol.
找不到那小子就別回來了
Tell them not to come back until he's found.
我們走
Let's go!
都出來
Get out!
你想去哪兒
Where you going?
她在哪兒 你個混蛋
Where is she, you son of a bitch?
見鬼 住手 住手
Shit! Hey! Wait!
好了 好了 行了
Come on, come on, come on.
我在這
I'm right here. I'm right here!
行了
- Okay, okay, okay. - All right. Okay.
我在這
I'm right here. I'm right here!
布倫達
Oh, Brenda.
你們別緊張
Everybody relax.
我們是同一戰線的
We're all on the same side here.
什麼同一戰線的 你到底是誰
What do you mean same side? Who the hell are you?
菜鳥
Hey, Greenie.
蓋
Gally?
不可能
No way.
不 等等
No, wait!
住手
Hold!
住手 沒事的
Stop! It's all right!
行了 住手 別打了
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Stop! Stop it!
住手
Stop.
- 他殺了查克 - 對 我知道
- He killed Chuck. - Yeah, I know.
我記得 我當時也在場 好嗎
I remember. I was there too, all right?
但我也記得
But I also remember that he was stung
他當時被怪物咬了神志不清
and half out of his mind.
先冷靜下來 好嗎
Just calm down. All right?
拜託
Come on.
就猜到會這樣
Kind of had that coming.
還有誰 煎鍋 紐特
Anybody else? Fry? Newt?
你認識這個人
Do you know this guy?
老相識了
He was an old friend.
怎麼會
How?
這怎麼可能
How is this possible?
我們看到你死了
We watched you die.
不 你們丟下我等死
No, you left me to die.
如果我們剛才沒找到你們
And if we hadn't found you when we did,
你們早就死了
you'd be dead right now.
你們來這幹什麼
What the hell are you doing here?
米諾
Minho.
實驗部抓了他
WICKED has him here.
我們在想辦法進去
We're looking for a way in.
我可以幫忙
I can help with that.
跟我來
Follow me.
我不會跟你去任何地方
I'm not going anywhere with you.
隨你的便吧
Suit yourself.
但我能帶你們進去
But I can get you through those walls.
離開迷宮後 一群前往城市的人
After the maze, I got picked up by a group
把我給救了
headed to the city.
他們發現我是免疫者
They realized I was immune, patched me up,
就帶我來這 交給了勞倫斯
and they brought me here to Lawrence.
實驗部控制城市後
This group's been at war with WICKED
這個組織就在和他們抗爭
ever since they took control of the city.
實驗部不可能永遠躲在牆後
But WICKED can't hide behind those walls forever.
總有一天
Day's gonna come, and they're gonna pay
他們會付出代價的
for what they've done.
聽好
Listen, uh,
他平時很少見外人
he doesn't get a lot of visitors.
所以 我來和他交談 好嗎
So, let me do the talking. All right?
別盯著他看
And try not to stare.
玫瑰香氣如此甜蜜
Rose took my nose, I suppose.
甜蜜 甜蜜 玫瑰香氣
如此甜蜜
Suppose, suppose, took my nose...
I suppose.
蓋
Gally,
你安全回來了就好
glad to see you made it back.
賈思珀都告訴我了
Jasper told me what happened.
那是一場屠殺
It was a slaughter.
我們抵擋不了那些重型武器
There's nothing we could do against those guns.
對
No,
他們既然膽敢捅馬蜂窩
but they can only poke the hornet's nest so long
就等著被蟄吧
before they get stung.
這些人是誰
Now, who are these people?
為什麼來這
Why are they here?
我們要進實驗部
We need to get into WICKED.
蓋婸“A能幫我們進去
Gally said you can get us through the walls.
蓋 你要學會一點
Gally should know better than to make promises
不要許下兌現不了的承諾
that he can't keep.
高牆不過是第一道難關
Besides, that wall is only half your problem.
混入實驗部基本不可能
Getting inside WICKED is impossible.
現在應該有個辦法了
There might be a way now.
但是沒有托馬斯就做不到
But it doesn't work without Thomas.
是這樣嗎
Is that so?
知道我是誰嗎
Do you know what I am...
托馬斯
Thomas?
我是一個生意人
I am a businessman.
所以我絕不會去冒不必要的風險
Which means that I don't take unnecessary risks.
我為什麼要相信你
Why should I trust you?
因為我能幫你
'Cause I can help you.
如果你能幫我穿過高牆
You see, if you can get me through those walls...
我就給你想要的
I can get you what you need.
你覺得我想要的是什麼
What is it that you think I need?
時間
Time.
每分每秒
Every last drop.
這就是我想要的嗎
Is that what I need?
實驗部有我們想要的
WICKED has something we both want.
那這樣吧
I'll tell you what.
你們進去兩個人
Two can go for now.
其他人和我待在這
The rest stay down here with me.
只是為了確保
Just a little insurance to make sure
你會老老實實地回來
you find your way back.
成交嗎
We have a deal?
蓋 給他帶路
Gally, show him the way.
小心點 托馬斯
Be careful, Thomas.
蓋 照顧好他們倆
Gally, take care of these two.
好
Yeah.
太噁心了
This is gross.
天哪
Jesus.
是啊 太棒了
Yeah, this is great.
跟著我 還要走很遠
Stay with me. We got a ways to go.
準備好了
We're ready.
夏安
Shai?
特瑞莎女士
Hi, Miss Teresa.
感覺怎麼樣
How are you feeling?
還好
Okay.
這能讓我好起來嗎
Is that gonna make me better?
我希望會
I hope so.
還記得你給我講的那個故事嗎
Do you remember the story you were telling me?
你從小住的房子
About the house you grew up in?
我 不 不記得了
I don't remember.
湖邊的那個
The one by the lake?
好燙啊
It burns.
別怕 別怕
I know, I know.
打完了 沒事了
There we go. All done.
你真勇敢
You're so brave.
真是不可思議
Oh, that is incredible.
什麼時候能給感染者注射
How soon can you administer to the infected?
你之前還下令朝人群開槍
You show a lot of compassion
現在還挺有同情心啊
for someone who just opened fire on a crowd.
你要我履行職責 有機會自然要把握住
You told me to do my job. I had a shot. I took it.
但很明顯失手了
And missed, apparently.
巡邏隊沒有發現屍體
The patrols never found a body.
托馬斯還活著呢
Thomas is still out there.
那特瑞莎呢
What about her?
她知道嗎
Does she know?
不
No.
別告訴她
She can't.
我需要她集中精力
I need her to stay focused.
馬上提升全市的安全級別
Elevate security levels throughout the city.
我就指望你把這些事處理好了 詹森
I'm counting on you to handle this, Janson.
紅區
Red zone,
列車五分鐘後駛離車站
departing the station in five minutes.
謝謝
Thank you.
這離迷宮中心遠著呢
This is a long way from the Glade.
十五分鐘後開始強制宵禁
Fifteen minutes to mandatory curfew.
請大家遵守秩序返回家中
Please proceed home in an orderly fashion.
注意 這是為了您的安全
Remember, this is for your safety.
感謝您的配合
Thank you for your compliance.
我們最好快離開街道
Yeah, we better get off these streets.
我知道很難 但是你們要擺出一副經歷過這種情況的樣子
And I know it's hard, but act like you've seen it before.
警戒程度提高不少
They've definitely upped security.
我看應該跟你們有關係吧
I'm guessing you shanks have something to do with that.
好了 我們先走
All right, let's get outta here.
行了 紐特 你先上
All right, Newt, you're up.
我自己來
I got it.
就是這
There it is.
他們抓了米諾
If WICKED's got Minho,
肯定關在這
that's where they'll be keeping him.
勞倫斯這些年來一直在想辦法混進去
Lawrence has been trying to find a way in for years.
但這堥麭B都是衛兵
Place is crawling with soldiers.
哪兒都有攝像頭
They got surveillance everywhere.
每層都有掃瞄儀
Scanners on every floor.
感覺就像個堡壘
Sounds like a bloody fortress.
你說有辦法進去的
Yeah, I thought you said you had a way in.
應該有
I might.
You might?
什麼叫應該有
What the hell do you mean "might"?
看看吧
Take a look.
我是說有辦法
I said I had a way in.
可沒說你會喜歡這辦法
I didn't say you were gonna like it.
不 肯定有別的辦法
No. There's gotta be another way.
什麼辦法 你看過那棟樓
Like what? You've seen the building.
她是我們唯一的方法
She is our only way in.
你覺得她會幫我們
You really think she's gonna help us?
我又沒說要去請她幫忙
I don't plan on asking for her permission.
是我聽錯了嗎
Am I missing something here?
你們說的是那個背叛過我們的女人 對吧
This is the same girl who betrayed us, correct?
那個賤人
Same dick?
我喜歡這種直爽的
I like her.
你怎麼回事
What's going on?
怎麼 怕你女朋友
What, are you afraid your little girlfriend's
會受傷嗎
gonna get hurt?
你果然不僅僅
Because this has obviously never been
是為了救米諾
just about rescuing Minho.
對吧
Has it?
紐特 你在說什麼
Wait, what are you talking about?
特瑞莎
Teresa.
要不是因為她
She's the only reason
米諾一開始也不會失蹤
that Minho's even missing in the first place.
現在終於有機會救他了
Now we finally have an opportunity to get him back.
結果呢 你又不願意了 因為她
And what? You don't want to because of her?
因為你心
Because deep down inside
還在乎她 對不對
you still care about her, don't you?
你承認吧
Just admit it.
紐特 我 不要對我撒謊
- Newt, I... - Don't lie to me!
不要對我撒謊
Don't lie to me!
抱歉
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
剛才的事 很抱歉
Sorry about that. Back there.
看樣子我是瞞不住了
I guess I can't hide this anymore.
為什麼不告訴我
Why didn't you tell me?
告訴你又有什麼用呢
Didn't think it would make any difference.
我知道實驗部
All I know is that WICKED must have put me
把我關進迷宮是有原因的
in that maze for a reason.
他們只想
Maybe it was literally
把你這樣的免疫者
just so they could tell the difference
和我這樣的普通人區分開來
between immunes like you and people like me.
我們還有希望
You know we can still fix this, Newt.
別放棄 好嗎
Okay? We can.
不要擔心我
Don't worry about me.
要緊的是米諾
This is about Minho.
他現在需要我們
Now he needs us.
所以就算只有萬分之一的機會
So if there is even the slightest chance
能救他出來
that we can save him,
只要有一點希望我們都要試一試
we can get him out of there, then we have to take that.
不管要付出什麼代價
No matter what the cost.
好 我明白了
Okay. I hear you.
抬他起來
Let's get him up.
米諾
Minho.
能聽見嗎
Can you hear me?
這埵陪茪p女孩
There's a little girl here.
她名叫夏安
Her name is Shai Lun.
她已經被感染了三個星期了
She's been infected for three weeks now.
但是米諾
But, Minho,
你能救她的命
you're going to save her.
而且你還能救很多人的命
And you can save so many others.
我們在這付出的努力
Everything we're doing here,
沒有白費
it's working.
你明白嗎
Do you understand?
所以我們的工作非常重要
That's why this is so important.
我只想讓你知道
I just wanted you to know.
特瑞莎
Teresa.
米諾
Minho?
你這個叛徒
You're a traitor!
我們那麼信你
We trusted you!
放開她
- Get off! - Hey, let her go!
放開我
Get off me! Get off me!
我要殺了你 你這個叛徒
I'll kill you! You traitor!
你把他們都害死了
You killed them all!
特瑞莎 醫學實驗室叫你
Teresa, they need you in the med lab.
好像很著急
It sounds serious.
我很遺憾 特瑞莎
I'm sorry, Teresa.
這不是你的錯
It's not your fault.
你真的已經盡力了
You did everything you could.
請大家注意 宵禁已經開始
This is an alert. Curfew is now in effect.
違反宵禁令外出者
Anyone caught in violation of curfew
將被立即驅逐出城
will be subject to immediate deportation.
托馬斯
Thomas?
Thomas.
特瑞莎
Hey, Teresa.
你不應該來的
You shouldn't be here.
如果詹森發現你在這
If Janson finds out you're here...
我不會久留
I'm not staying.
我只是
It's just, uh...
要見見你
I had to see you.
想問你個問題
I have to ask you something.
背叛了我們
Do you regret it?
你後悔嗎
What you did to us?
有時候會
Sometimes.
但我做了我認為對的事
But I did what I thought was right.
要是能重來 我還會這麼做
I'd do it again.
很好
Good.
難得放鬆一下是嗎
Taking the edge off, I see.
多漂亮的城市
Beautiful, isn't it?
是啊
Yes.
真漂亮
- It's a lovely city. - Hmm.
那些牆
The walls.
當人們命懸一線時
It's amazing what people can accomplish
總會爆發非凡的力量
when their survival's at stake.
只要逼得夠緊 他們就沒什麼做不到的
Squeeze them hard enough, there's nothing they can't do.
沒什麼底線不能打破
No line they won't cross.
這只是一個小挫折
You've had a bit of a setback.
我們早就習慣挫折了
It's nothing we're not used to.
這次不一樣
Not this time.
病毒通過空氣
The virus is airborne.
已經傳到城堣F
It's inside the walls.
那個血清是最後的希望
That serum was our last chance.
頂多一個月內 所有人都會受到感染
Anyone not already infected will be inside of a month.
好吧
Okay.
我們還有辦法
We can handle this.
只需要撤離關鍵人員
We just need to evacuate essential personnel,
然後繼續北上在建立一個安全區
set up at another safe zone farther north.
這棟樓媮晹酗G十八名免疫者
We've still got 28 immunes right inside this building.
我們還能找到更多
We can find more.
我相信
You would.
你會抓住所有的免疫者
You'd hunt every last one of them down
直到一個也不剩
till there was no one left.
儘管我們這樣殘忍地利用他們
In spite of everything we've done to them,
讓他們受盡了折磨
everything we've put them through.
但至少我們給了
At least we gave them the tools
他們生存的希望
they'll need to survive.
也許他們能做到我們做不到的
Maybe they'll succeed where we've failed.
你這是告訴我你要放棄嗎
Are you really telling me that you're giving up?
付出了那麼多
After everything?
我不是要放棄 詹森
It's not about giving up, Janson.
是要做好失敗的心理準備
It's about knowing when you've lost.
蓋
Gally?
接下來我們這麼辦
Here's how this is gonna go.
我們要問你幾個問題
We're gonna ask you some questions,
而你要老實回答我們
and you're gonna tell us exactly what we need to know.
我們從簡單的開始  米諾在哪兒
We'll start off simple. Where's Minho?
你們不會真的以為...
You guys don't seriously think...
不要看他
Don't look at him.
你為什麼要看他
Why are you looking at him?
看我
Look at me.
他不會幫你的
He's not gonna help you.
我們知道你們把米諾關在那棟樓
Now, we know you have Minho in the building.
哪一層？
Where?
他和其他人都在關押區
He's with the others in holding.
地下三層
Sublevel three.
其他人有多少？
How many others?
二十八個
28.
我都能救出去
I can make that work.
不  你們不明白
No. No, you guys don't understand.
整層樓都是限製出入的
The whole level's restricted.
你們沒有指紋認證根本進不去
You can't get in without a thumbprint ID.
所以要你跟我們一起去
That's why you're gonna come with us.
那可不一定
Well, I don't know.
我們也不一定需要她
We don't necessarily need her.
對吧
Right?
不用整個人
Not all of her.
- 有指紋就夠了 - 蓋  你夠了
- We just need her finger. - Gally, back off.
你覺得過分了？
What, are you squeamish?
我敢說她對米諾做的事肯定更過分
I guarantee you she's done a lot worse to Minho.
這不是我們的計劃  你讓開
That's not the plan. Back off.
沒有區別的
It won't make a difference.
你們怎麼對我都行
Do whatever you want to me.
但你們是進不去的
You still won't get through the front door.
傳感器會發現你們
The sensors will pick you up the...
我們知道 因為我們...被植入了芯片
We know. We're tagged.
實驗部資產
Property of WICKED.
你也能幫我們摘掉
You're gonna help us with that, too.
放鬆一點  會有點疼
Try to relax. This is gonna sting.
你快動手吧
Let's just get it over with.
她很享受吧
She enjoyed that.
你也許是對的
You're probably right.
給你  看合不合適
Here. See if these fit.
- 謝謝 - 謝謝  紐特
- Thanks. - Thanks, Newt.
該出發了  老頭子
Better get going, old man.
路可遠著呢
Long road ahead of you.
你真的不聽我的勸嗎
You sure I can't talk you out of this?
現在還來得及
It's your last chance.
我不像你總喜歡逃避戰鬥
You know, it's not like you to shy away from a fight.
追求戰鬥也不是你的個性
And it's not like you to go looking for one.
我只是忍不住想 一旦我走出門
I just can't help but think if I walk out that door...
就再也見不到你了
I'm never gonna see you again.
仔細想想  我們什麼時候開始為陌生人出生入死了
Since when do we go sticking our necks out for strangers?
我也曾是你的陌生人
I was a stranger once, too.
-隻是別讓我們等太久  -不
- Just don't leave us hanging. - No.
不會的
Never.
她看起來很好
She's looking good.
很健康
Healthy.
你們給她注射血清了
How've you been getting her serum?
你在說什麼
What are you talking about?
布倫達
Brenda.
我沒想到她能活下來
I didn't think she'd still be alive.
上次治療是什麼時候？
When was her last treatment?
在干將組織
At the Right Arm.
上次見你的時候
The last time we saw you.
那都好幾個月前了
But that was months ago.
托馬斯  這根本不可能
Thomas, that's not possible.
她現在應該已經發作了啊
She should have turned by now.
她怎麼可能還能...
There's no way she could possibly still...
夠了  別說了
All right, that's enough.
你不相信我嗎？
You don't believe me?
你覺得我能信你嗎？
Do you really expect me to?
你做出了選擇
You made your choice.
你們倆沒事吧
Everything okay over here?
沒事
Yeah.
我們說完了
Yeah, we're done.
想得美
Nice try.
你愛過她的  對嗎？
You were in love with her, weren't you?
我不知道
I don't know.
你要注意一點
Just be careful.
你的軟肋
You sort of have this problem
就是沒法拋下別人
where you can't walk away from people.
即使你應當拋下
Even when you should.
你拯救不了所有人  托馬斯
You can't save everyone, Thomas.
總得試試
I can try.
別停下
Don't stop.
快
Go, go, go.
等等
Hold on. Hold on.
這個我能搞定
I can get in here.
-待著別動  -對講機給我
Stay there. Throw me the walkie.
煎鍋  我們進來了  你那邊怎樣？
Frypan, we're in. How you doing?
好  快了  我也快到了
Yeah, I'm getting there.
代我向米諾問好
Tell Minho "Hi," for me.
堅持住  夥計
Hang in there, buddy.
這就行了
This'll work.
布倫達  你那邊怎樣
Brenda, what's your status?
不怎麼樣  我在想辦法
Status is, I'm working on it.
收到  確保你那邊準備好了
Copy. Just make sure you're ready on your end.
不用擔心  我會準時到那兒的
Don't worry. You know I'm gonna be there.
我們走
All right, let's go.
收到信號了
We got a signal.
蓋媟d定了
Gally did it.
我們黑進去了
We're in.
很好
Good.
放開手腳干
Give me everything.
徹底控制那
I want full control.
奇怪  系統故障了
That's funny. System's glitching.
我出去看看
I'll go check it out.
走吧  快點  走
Get back, get back! Move!
快點  我們走
Come on, let's go.
沒事
- Get them open. - Let's go.
來吧  我們走
It's okay. You guys are okay. Come on.
紐特 去看看另一間牢房
Come on, let's go. Newt, check the other cell.
你們沒事了  快走吧
Come on, you guys are okay. Come on.
保險庫  怎麼進去
The vault. How do I get in?
進不去的
You can't.
大家快點  快走
Come on, guys. Come on.
各位
Guys,
可能要花些時間
this might take some time.
見鬼
Shit.
他不在這兒
He's not here.
他人在哪兒
Where is he?
真的不能等到明早嗎
This really couldn't wait till morning?
一次注射這麼大劑量
You realize this could kill him, right?
他會沒命的  你知道嗎
Taking this much, all at once.
我只是執行命令
I have my orders.
是詹森要求的
Janson wants it all.
有人把米諾帶去醫學部了
Somebody's moved him up to the medical wing.
托馬斯  那是大樓的另一邊
Thomas, that's on the other side of the building.
好  這就帶我去找他
Okay, take me to him. Right now.
我要跟你一起去
All right. I'm coming with you.
紐特  你不能去 聽著
Newt, no, you're not.
你留在這  等蓋堮釣鴞撗M
You have to stay here, wait with Gally for the serum.
你不能一個人冒險
You can't do this on your own.
米諾之前不就是那樣麼
Minho comes first, remember?
快走吧  別浪費時間了
Just go. We're wasting time.
我會搞到血清的  我們在外面會合
I'll get the serum. We'll meet you out back.
-好吧  我們走  -走吧
Okay, fine. Let's go. Come on.
嘿  菜鳥
Hey, Greenie.
祝你好運
Good luck.
不要停
Keep moving.
快點 快點
Come on, come on.
等等
Hold it.
熬夜工作了吧
You're working late.
特瑞莎  我就喜歡你這一點
See, that's what I like about you, Teresa.
不管有多困難
No matter how bleak things get, you just...
你都不曾放棄
Well, you never give up.
現在這種情況
Times like this,
你需要一個靠得住的朋友
you need a friend that you can count on.
我會留心的
I'll bear that in mind.
有件事應該告訴你
There is one thing you should know.
但別說是我說的
One friend to another.
托馬斯就在城
Thomas is here.
我們的監控在牆外發現他了
A surveillance picked him up outside the walls.
艾娃不想讓你知道
Ava didn't want you to know,
但托馬斯可能會嘗試找你
but there is a chance that he may try to contact you,
如果你見到他了...
and if he does,
那麼我希望你能第一時間通知我
I'd like to think that I'd be your first call.
你會殺了他嗎？
Are you going to kill him?
有問題嗎？
Would that be a problem?
我到了
This is me.
托馬斯  你先聽我說
Thomas, you have to listen to me.
拿到血清也救不了紐特
Getting that serum won't save Newt.
只能讓他活久一點  但是...
It might buy him some time, but...
別聽她的
Just ignore her.
她想要給你洗腦
She's trying to get inside your head.
托馬斯  聽我說 你知道外面的情況
Thomas, listen. You know what's going on out there.
人類要滅絕了  世界要毀滅了
People are dying. The world is dying.
你血液的情況我覺得有些異常
There's something about your blood I don't understand.
開門
Open it.
讓我做幾個測試吧
If you let me run some tests...
我保證會保護你的
I promise I can protect you.
是嗎  像保護米諾那樣
Yeah? Like you protected Minho?
你這是幹什麼
What are you doing?
你們還要犧牲多少人
How many people is it gonna take?
你們要抓捕
How many more people do they have to round up,
折磨  殺害多少人 才夠
torture, kill?
什麼時候才會結束
Huh? When the hell does it stop?
等找到解藥就結束了
It stops when we find a cure.
根本就沒有什麼解藥
There is no goddamn cure!
別白費口舌了  特瑞莎
Don't waste your breath, Teresa.
他早就做出選擇了
He made his choice long ago.
把槍放下
Drop it, kid!
退後 叫他們退後
Back up. Tell them to back off.
叫他們退後
Tell them to back off!
嘿  托馬斯
Hey, Thomas, come on.
是我
It's me.
我認識你很多年了
I've known you longer than you can remember.
你不會朝她開槍的
You're not gonna shoot her.
你以為我不敢
You don't think so?
好啊
Okay.
來啊
Go on then.
開槍啊
Shoot her.
證明給我看
Prove me wrong.
開槍
Shoot her.
讓開 讓開
Clear! Clear!
快 快
Move! Move!
你要好好解釋一下這是什麼情況
Your story better be good.
我這是幫了你的忙
I just did you a favor.
門鎖死了 他們逃不出去
Doors are sealed. They can't get out.
詹森 我要你活捉他們
Janson, I need them alive.
快來
- Come on. Come on! - All right, let's move!
快來三樓
Yes, sir! Level three, now!
我們馬上逃出去
Okay. We need to get outta here now.
大家在一起 跟緊我
You stay close to me. Stick together.
你拿好這個 拼了命去保護它 明白了麼
You, you guard this with your life. You understand?
好了
All right.
我們走
Let's go.
封鎖大樓 派人去20樓
Lock down the building. Send everyone up to 20.
來人把那該死的警報給關上
And someone shut off those goddamn sirens!
是 長官
Yes, sir.
快快快
Move! Move!
把頭埋低
Stay low! Stay low!
快快快
Go! Go! Go!
把頭埋低
Go! Stay low! Stay low!
布倫達 你在哪 我們來了
Brenda, where are you? We're here.
快上車 快快快
Come on, let's go.
我們走 快快快
All right. Let's go, let's go. Quickly, quickly.
快上車 快快快
Front and back, front and back. Let's go.
托馬斯在哪
Wait, where's Thomas?
我還以為她跟你會合了呢
I was hoping he was with you.
慢著
Come on.
你在這跟孩子們在一起
Wait! Wait! Stay here with the kids.
在這等著
Wait here...
我去找他
I'll find him.
在這等著
Just wait for us, okay?
我們哪都不去
We're not going anywhere.
有蹤跡了麼
Anything?
他們不在這 長官
No sign of them yet, sir.
他們肯定在這
Yeah, well, they're here somewhere.
他們逃不出去的 找到他們
They can't get out. Find them.
你們兩個 去那邊
You two, that way.
剩下的人 跟我來 我們走
The rest of you, follow me. Let's go.
是 長官
- Yes, sir! - Affirmative.
代碼22 已生效
Code 22 in progress.
所有R-16等級的工作人員 請到制定崗位報道
All R-16 personnel, report to their assigned stations.
趴下
Get down. Get down.
上上上
Move! Move! Move!
別出聲
Stay quiet.
車上有人
Got someone here.
對不住了 托馬斯
Sorry, Thomas.
車上有人
Hey, someone's got the bus.
坐穩了
Hold on!
停車
- Watch it! - Stop!
不不不
No, no, no!
沒事的
It's all right!
上車 上車
Load up! Load up!
追追追
Let's go! Move it!
Move! Move!
所有R-16等級的工作人員
All R-16 personnel,
請到制定崗位報道
report to their assigned stations.
托馬斯 快走
Thomas! No!
米諾 米諾
Minho? Minho!
- 媽的 - 不許動
- Oh, shit! - Freeze!
米諾
Minho!
米諾 你在哪
Minho, where are you?
米諾
Minho!
醫生 他醒了
Doctor, he's coming out of it.
在注射鎮定劑
Get me another sedative.
他媽的
Shit!
他們在這
Over here! There they are!
我來堵截他
I'll cut him off!
紐特 趴下
Newt, get down!
該死  沒子彈了
Shit! I'm almost out.
退後
Get back.
漂亮
Nice. All right.
快走  咱們走  快
Let's go! Go!
你們兩個站住
You two, freeze!
趴到地上
Get down on the ground. Now!
快點 我叫你們趴...
I said get your...
米諾
Minho.
這是真的嗎
Is this real?
-找到了  -快跑
I got him! I got him! Over here.
追 這邊
Go! This way!
快點
Come on!
你們三個站住
You three! Stop!
在這邊
Come on.
快
In here, in here.
紐特  快來
Newt, come on.
找人給我把門弄開
Somebody get this door open.
是  頭兒
Yes, sir!
該死
Oh, shit.
有辦法嗎
Any ideas?
大概吧
Maybe.
好吧  勉強能行
Okay, it's doable.
只是需要個助跑
Just need a little running start.
就快弄開了
Almost through.
你確定能行嗎
You sure about this?
不怎麼確定
Not really.
那你很棒哦
Nice pep talk.
就是  厲害到不行
Yeah, we're all bloody inspired.
-進去  -該死
- Move it! Move it! - Shit.
快  快
Go! Go!
托馬斯
Thomas!
哦不
Oh, shit!
-米諾  你沒事吧  -沒事
- Minho, you okay? - Yeah.
你們三個都別動
You three, don't move.
你在逗我吧
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
別亂動哦
Take it easy.
想都別想
Uh-uh-uh! Don't even think about it.
跪到地上  舉起手來
Get on your knees with your hands in the air.
你個混蛋
You son of a bitch.
蓋
Gally?
米諾
Minho.
你們瘋了吧
You guys are nuts.
等會兒再跟你解釋
I'll explain later.
所有工作人員請留在各自的房間
Attention all personnel.
派人去搜
Drop the net.
執行戒嚴令  嚴禁任何人進出
Declare martial law. No one leaves until they're found.
安排好了  我們已經掌握了公交車的行蹤
It's done, sir. We already have eyes on the bus.
我們的人正在追捕
Our patrols are in pursuit.
什麼公交車？
What bus?
該死 坐穩了
Shit! Hold on!
見鬼
Shit!
全都給我下車
Get out of the vehicle.
別動
Don't move.
你們做得很好
You're doing great.
走到離車遠點
Now step away from the vehicle.
我叫你離車遠點
I said step away from the vehicle!
把手舉起來
Put your hands in the air.
把槍放下
Drop the weapon!
好了
Here we go.
給我沖  給我沖 快
Push in! Push in! Go! Go!
別讓那輛車逃了 快  抓住他們
- That bus does not leave! - Move! Move in!
快點  找東西抓緊了
Come on, hold on to something!
我們走了
Here we go.
包圍住  快  快  不要開火
Circle up! Go! Go! Hold fire!
都抓緊了
Brace yourself.
抱歉
Sorry.
真該死
Shit.
找東西抓緊了
Hold on to something!
好了  大家下車
Okay. Everybody off.
閉嘴
Shut up.
他們還沒逃出去
They're not out yet.
他們肯定氣瘋了
Well, they're definitely pissed.
隧道還有多遠
How far are the tunnels?
大概還有十二條街吧
Uh, maybe 12 blocks from here.
我們能趕上的
We can make it.
紐特  你還好嗎
Newt, how are you feeling?
不好
Terrible.
總算見到你了
It's good to see you though.
他變成這樣多久了
How long has he been like this?
他不會有事的  我們去找布倫達
He'll be okay. We just gotta get to Brenda.
她有血清
She's got the serum.
好了  我們走
Come on, let's go.
紐特  堅持住
Hey, Newt.
我們來扶你  走吧
Come on, bud. We gotta get you up. Let's go.
-不要緊吧  -沒事
- You okay? - Yeah.
你為什麼要幫我們 蓋
Why you helping us, Gally?
我在你胸口開了個洞
I put a spear through your chest.
沒錯
Yeah.
不過人無完人
Nobody's perfect, man.
勞倫斯
Lawrence!
等等  孩子們  等等
Wait, guys. Wait, wait, wait.
他們人呢
Where is everyone?
先在這等等
Wait here, guys. Wait.
托馬斯
Thomas!
勞倫斯
Lawrence!
所有東西都不見了
Everything's gone.
不要怕
Don't be scared.
也許我長得不好看
I may not be pretty,
但我們都認得敵人的長相
but we all know who the enemies are,
他們就躲在這堵牆後面
cowering behind those walls!
沒錯 他們起了個名字
They have a name
來稱呼像我們這樣的人
for people like us in there.
他們叫我們狂客
They call us Cranks!
但要我說 他們才是怪物
But I say that they are the monsters.
是他們發起的這場戰爭
They're the ones who started this war,
但是今晚
but tonight,
我們要終結它
we will finish it.
跟著我
Follow me.
跟著我  讓他們好好認識一下
Follow me, and we will show them
他們選擇
the faces of the people
遺忘的這些面孔
that they have chosen to forget!
跟著我著座城市就是你們的了
Follow me and this city is yours!
準備出發
Let's move it!
我們走
Let's go!
控制台  你們看到了嗎
Control, you seeing this?
請求指示
Please advise.
我的天
Holy shit.
一號  二號炮塔準備開火
Get turrets one and two ready to fire.
手動控制失敗  拒絕訪問
Guns aren't responding. I'm locked out.
炮塔沒有反應 我被鎖死了
All right. Move forward.
快過來  向前靠 開火  開火
Open fire! Open fire!
我們的目標是實驗部
We're supposed to take down WICKED,
不是整座城市
not the whole damn city.
蓋  走吧
Gally, come on.
現在發佈強制撤離命令
This is a mandatory evacuation.
最後一班車將在38分鐘後出發
The last transport leaves in 38 minutes.
請前往屋頂集合
Please proceed to the roof.
重複一遍  現在發佈強制撤離命令
I repeat, this is a mandatory evacuation.
特瑞莎 你還留在這幹什麼  我們得走了
Teresa, what are you still doing here? We have to leave.
不  我還不能走 我要等托馬斯
No, I can't leave. Not without Thomas.
太晚了  他已經走了
It's too late for that. He's gone.
不 你還不明白
No. You don't understand.
我需要多一點 過來
I need more.
你看
Come. Look.
它不止減緩了病毒的擴散
It's not just slowing the virus down.
還在摧毀它們
It's destroying it.
我們要找到托馬斯
We need to find Thomas.
隧道就在前面了
Tunnels are right up ahead.
見鬼
Shit!
蹲下  蹲下  躲起來
Hey! Stay low! Stay low!
糟了
Shit!
準備好
Get ready!
繼續前進  快快
All right, move up! Move up!
該死
Frontline down!
他們在等什麼
Damn it!
躲起來  趴下
What are they waiting for?
趴下
Get down, get down!
Stay down! Stay down!
該死  我們快走  快走
We gotta go. We gotta go.
快點  我們走  趕快走
Come on. Let's move, let's move.
布倫達  布倫達  你在嗎
Brenda, are you there?
托馬斯  我在這
Thomas, I'm here.
-你沒事吧  -見鬼
Shit! You okay?
我們可能出不去了
We're not gonna make it.
你什麼意思
Wait, what are you talking about?
別讓他們跑了
Don't let them get away!
帶其他人走 趁還不晚
Just take the others. Get everybody out
把大家帶出去
while you still can.
不行
No.
布倫達
Brenda.
我不會拋下你們的
I'm not leaving you.
懂了嗎
Okay?
想都別想
So forget it.
即使你應當拋下？
Even though you should?
來了 托馬斯 不用擔心 我會去找你的
Thomas, don't worry. I'm coming to you.
你什麼意思
What are you talking about?
我們的救兵來啦
Our ride's here!
到隧道附近找我們
Just look for us near the tunnels.
好了  咱們走  孩子們  快  救兵到了
Let's go, guys! Move! Our ride's here!
當心  跟上
- Careful. - Move! Move!
當心腳下  當心點  好嗎
Watch your step. Okay?
文斯？
Vince?
見到你真高興
Hey, it's good to see you, too.
是啊 我知道
Yeah, I know.
我讓他搭了便車
I picked up a stray.
我們趕緊溜吧
Let's get out of here, all right?
還不能走
We're not done yet.
托馬斯還在堶惟O
Thomas is still inside.
那就去救他們唄
Well, let's go get him then.
太棒了  我們走
- Hell yeah. - All right, let's go.
好了  快上來
- On board. Everybody. - Let's go! Step up! Step up!
我們要走了  大家快上來
- We gotta move, we gotta move. - Take a seat, harness...
好了  紐特  我們快到了
All right. Newt, we're almost there.
你們別管我了
Just leave me.
我的老天
Back! Back!
退後  退後
Let's go! Let's go!
我們上  幹掉他們
Take 'em out!
他們來了
- Okay, that's them. - Yeah.
他們來了 我們該走了  快走
It's them. We gotta go.
你們別管我了  趕快去
- We gotta go. - Go without me, man.
你們...
You should just...
米諾
Minho.
你先跑過去  拿到血清
You gotta run ahead, grab the serum,
然後盡快再跑回來
and get back to us as soon as you can.
-米諾  -去吧
Minho, go.
他說得對  我來掩護你
He's right. I can cover.
謝謝你
Thank you.
謝謝你  米諾
Thank you, Minho.
你要挺住
Hey, you just hang on.
你聽見了嗎
You hear me?
走  米諾  快走
Go, Minho, go!
好了  他們過去了
Okay, they're through.
紐特 紐特
Newt? Newt?
嘿 紐特
Hey! Hey! Newt! Hey!
我們要搏一搏
We're gonna try this. Okay?
我來扶你 好嗎
We gotta move, now. Let's get you up, come on.
現在就走  快   -走吧  快點  -不  托馬斯
- Let's go, come on. - No. No, Thomas.
紐特  紐特 我們真的得走了
No, Newt. Later. Later. Really gotta go.
- 快點 -你拿著這個
- Come on. - Look, you gotta take this.
-我先扶你起來 - 我叫你拿著！
- We gotta get you up, now. - No, just take it!
拜託
Please.
求你了托馬斯
Please, Tommy. Please.
好吧
All right.
好了  我要你帶東西
All right. I need you to give me everything you got.
一起跟我走 馬上走  好嗎  撐住
You and me, right now. Let's go. You ready?
好了嗎 準備好
Come on, ready? Here we go.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
大家別出來  別出來
Get back, guys, get back!
我的天
Oh, man.
沒事的 我們馬上離開這
It's okay, guys. We're getting out of here soon.
我們不能再久留了
We can't stay here, Bren.
別著急  他們會來的
Don't worry. They'll be here.
快點 快點
Come on. Come on.
就快到了  紐特  跟我來  挺住
We're almost there, Newt. Stay with me, come on.
不  紐特
Newt, no, no. Hey!
撐住
Come on.
托馬斯
Thomas?
你能聽到嗎
Can you hear me?
我需要你聽我說
I need you to listen to me.
我知道你沒有理由相信我
I know you have no reason to trust me,
但我需要你回來
but I need you to come back.
托馬斯  你可以拯救紐特
Thomas, you can save Newt.
他還有時間
There's still time for him.
布倫達病情的好轉是有原因的
There's a reason Brenda isn't sick anymore.
是因為你的血
It's your blood.
你明白嗎
Do you understand?
她沒病發是因為...
She isn't sick,
因為你治好了她
because you cured her.
你能救的不止她一個
She doesn't have to be the only one.
你只要回來就行了
All you have to do is come back.
我們一起結束這一切
And this will all finally be over.
求你了
Please.
回來我這吧
Just come back to me.
我知道你會做出正確的...
I know you'll do the right...
紐特？
Newt?
紐特
紐特  紐特  是我
Newt? Newt, it's me. It's me!
布倫達
Brenda!
血清在哪
Where's the serum?
托馬斯 殺了我
Tommy, kill me!
紐特  我在這
Newt, I'm here.
紐特  別這樣
Newt, please!
求你了
Please!
真的對不起  對不起  托馬斯
I'm sorry, Tommy.
沒事的  沒事的
It's okay. It's okay.
不
No!
布倫達
Brenda!
托馬斯
Thomas!
趴下  快趴下
Stay down, stay down!
紐特
Newt.
托馬斯
Tommy.
不
No, no.
不  不
No, no, no.
紐特
Newt?
是真的嗎
Is it true?
紐特
Newt.
我能救他的嗎
Could I have saved him?
你能拯救所有人
You can save us all.
沒事了
It's okay.
放其他人走好嗎
Just leave the others alone.
我保證
I promise.
我會...
I will...
噢  托馬斯
Oh, Thomas.
托馬斯 你應該逃跑的
You should have run.
托馬斯
Thomas.
聽到了嗎
Can you hear me?
你知道這是什麼地方嗎  托馬斯
Do you know what this place is, Thomas?
這是救生船
It's a lifeboat.
整個世界就要被淹沒了
And the whole world might be sinking,
但不代表我們也要跟著沉沒
but doesn't mean that we have to go down with it.
還要多久
How much longer?
快了
It's almost done.
為什麼不直接殺了我？
Why don't you just kill me?
殺了你？
Kill you?
我才捨不得殺你呢
No, we don't wanna do that.
我們會精心照顧你的
We're gonna take special care of you.
讓你好好活著
We'll keep you alive.
只不過...
Just.
作為回報
And in return,
你得為我們剩下的人續命
you will give life to the rest of us.
當然是我來選擇救誰
The ones we choose to save, anyway.
當然這並不夠拯救所有人
Of course, there's not gonna be enough for everyone.
我們必須做出困難的選擇
Hard choices are gonna have to be made.
耀斑病毒早晚有一天會消失
In time, the Flare virus will burn itself out.
可唯一的問題在於
The only question is,
哪些人能活到那一天
who will be the ones left standing?
多虧了你 還有這個
And thanks to you, to this,
我們終於可以選擇
we finally get to choose.
自己親手創造一個未來
A future of our own making.
祝你健康
To your health.
好了  我們趕緊走
Okay, let's get out of here.
拜託
Come on.
不
No!
你給我回來
Get back here.
回來
Get back!
不
No!
把它給我！
Give it to me.
Give it to me!
特瑞莎！
Teresa!
好啊  來啊
Come on.
好了
Okay.
夠了
That's enough.
準備武器
Weapons ready!
聽我指揮
On my command.
裝彈
Charge it!
準備
Ready.
開火
Fire!
特瑞莎
Teresa!
該死  我們得逃出去
We need to get out of here.
怎麼了
What's wrong?
托馬斯？
Thomas?
托馬斯！
Thomas!
-沒事  我們要  -見鬼
- Okay. Okay, we need to... - Oh, shit...
拜託  在哪  這
Find something. Here. Here!
這樣  用手壓住傷口  按住
Just put pressure on it. Hold it.
你...你快走吧
You gotta go.
你快走吧
不
No.
要走一起走
Not without you.
我必須承認  特瑞莎  你把我耍了
I admit, Teresa, you had me fooled.
我還以為我們是朋友
I thought we were friends.
也許你的本能就是
Maybe it's just in your nature to betray
會背叛你親近的人
the people closest to you.
出來吧
Come on.
不要再拖拉了
Let's not prolong this.
我們都清楚你們逃不掉的了
We both know there's no way outta here.
不要再給
Let's not make this any more painful
自己增加傷痛了
than it needs to be.
托馬斯
Thomas.
特瑞莎
Teresa.
不  不
No. No.
你好像拿了我的東西
I think you have something of mine.
不是那個
Not that.
他人在哪
Where is he?
拿這個走吧
Just take it.
放過他吧
Leave him alone.
你們兩個怎麼回事
What is it with you two?
你以為他很特別嗎
You think he's so special?
他是只小白鼠 天生免疫病毒
He's a lab rat. He was born with a gift.
不用靠後天的努力 去和病毒抗爭
He never had to fight for it, he never earned it.
他根本就配不上
He doesn't deserve it.
也許吧
Maybe.
但他就是他
But it's his.
你怎麼想  托馬斯
What about you, Thomas?
你不想說點什麼嗎
What do you have to say?
你的手上沾的血還不夠嗎
Don't you have enough blood on your hands already?
你也許沒法向她開槍
You might not have been able to shoot her.
但我可以
But I can.
行吧  好
Okay. Fine.
隨便你吧
Have it your way.
詹森
Janson.
你打偏了  小兔崽子
Missed, you little shit.
是嗎
Did I?
該死
Oh, shit.
快走  我們趕緊走
Come on. We need to go.
走這邊  這
This way. Here.
這
Come on.
快
對不起  我...
I'm sorry.
我盡力了
I tried.
我...我知道
I know.
我好像看到他了
I think I got him.
對對  就是他  我去開門
Yeah, that's him. I'll get the hatch.
好了  找到他了  快點
All right, I got him, I got him.
快走
Let's go, let's go.
快呀
Come on.
不
No!
我沒法再靠近了
I can't get any closer.
托馬斯
Thomas!
快
Now!
拜託  拜託
Come on, come on, come on.
快點  快點  托馬斯
- Come on! - Come on, Thomas!
把手給我
Give me your hand!
再近一點
Get closer!
跳啊
Jump!
低點
Lower!
快 不
No!
你們得再靠近一點
You gotta get closer.
伸手  該死
Come on!
再來 好  快點  過來  撐住  近點
- Come on, reach! Come on! - Reach!
抓住他  拉他上來  用力
- Pull him up! - Pull!
上來
Come on!
快呀
特瑞莎
Teresa!
不
No!
我們經歷了漫長的征途
We have come a long way together.
無數人犧牲了生命
So many have sacrificed so much
才最終建立了這個家園
to make this place possible.
有我們的朋友
Your friends
我們的家人
and your family.
這一杯敬沒能在這兒的夥伴
So here's to the ones who couldn't be here.
敬我們失去的朋友
Here's to the friends we lost.
這堿O你們的歸宿  所有人的家
This place is for you. It's for all of us.
但是這個
But this,
是他們的長眠之處
this is for them.
所以用你們自己的時間 用你們自己的方式
So, in your own time, in your own way,
找到平靜吧
come make your peace.
歡迎來到避風港
And welcome to the Safe Haven.
想吃東西嗎
You all want some food?
這媟|成為我們安穩的家
This is gonna be a good home for us.
是啊
Yeah.
你昏迷的時候還拿著這個
You had this on you while you were passed out.
我保管得還不錯吧
Figured I'd keep it safe for ya.
謝謝  米諾
Thanks, Minho.
待會見
See you out there.
See ya.
親愛的托馬斯
Dear Thomas...
這是我有記憶以來寫的第一封信
This is the first letter I can remember writing.
雖然我不知道進迷宮之前我有沒有寫過
Obviously, I don't know if I wrote any before the maze.
但是即使這不是我寫的第一封 這也應該是最後一封
But even if it's not my first, it's likely to be my last.
我想讓你知道  我不曾害怕
I want you to know that I'm not scared.
至少我怕的不是死亡
Well, not of dying, anyway.
而是忘卻
It's more forgetting.
病毒奪走我的記憶
It's losing myself to this virus.
才是我最為害怕的
That's what scares me.
所以我每晚都大聲念出他們的名字
So every night I've been saying their names out loud.
艾爾比
Alby...
溫斯頓  查克
Winston, Chuck.
一遍又一遍地重複著
And I just repeat them over and over,
像做禱告一樣
like a prayer,
然後記憶就會湧現出來
and it all comes flooding back.
都是些小事
Just the little things, like the way
比如夕陽
the sun used to hit the Glade
沉下高牆前
at that perfect moment right before
餘暉掛在林間空地的那一剎那
it slipped beneath the walls.
我還想起了煎鍋燉的菜
And I remember the taste of Frypan's stew.
想不到我會這麼懷念那東西
I never thought I'd miss that stuff so much.
我也會想起你
And I remember you.
記得你一開始走出籠子
I remember the first time you came up in the Box.
還是個驚慌失措
Just a scared little Greenie
連名字都想不起來的小子
who couldn't even remember his own name.
但從你衝進迷宮的那一刻起
But from that moment you ran into the maze,
我就知道我會追隨你
I knew I would follow you anywhere.
我做到了
And I have.
我們都做到了
We all have.
如果有機會我能重新來過
If I could do it all over again, I would
我還會做出同樣的選擇
and I wouldn't change a thing.
而我也希望
And my hope for you
等你多年後回想起來的時候
is that when you're looking back years from now,
你也能說出同樣的話
you'll be able to say the same.
未來就在你手中了  托馬斯
The future's in your hands now, Tommy.
我相信你會找到正確的道路的
And I know you'll find a way to do what's right.
你一定能的
You always have.
幫我照顧好大家
Take care of everyone for me.
也照顧好你自己
And take care of yourself.
你值得擁有幸福
You deserve to be happy.
多謝你做我的朋友
Thank you for being my friend.
再見了  兄弟
Goodbye, mate.
紐特
Newt.
HDZIMU中文字幕網 http://www.hdzimu.com
本站字幕僅供翻譯學習交流,禁止用於商業用途
最新字幕請關注新浪微博:HDZIMU中文字幕網